<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>https://ergonautkb.com/ru/blog</id>
    <title>Ergonaut Keyboards Blog</title>
    <updated>2023-11-06T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
    <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://ergonautkb.com/ru/blog"/>
    <subtitle>Ergonaut Keyboards Blog</subtitle>
    <icon>https://ergonautkb.com/ru/img/favicon.ico</icon>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Introducing the Ergonaut One]]></title>
        <id>https://ergonautkb.com/ru/blog/introducing-ergonaut-one</id>
        <link href="https://ergonautkb.com/ru/blog/introducing-ergonaut-one"/>
        <updated>2023-11-06T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hand-drawn abstract orange swirls on white background symbolizing connectivity]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" alt="Hand-drawn abstract orange swirls on white background symbolizing connectivity" src="https://ergonautkb.com/ru/assets/images/a6f3a217-191c-4831-972b-e67b66d6c321-2c37cb1be0522942952281edb7a5d920.webp" width="1792" height="1024" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>We're thrilled to announce the launch of the <a href="https://ergonautkb.com/ru/docs/keyboards/ergonaut-one/intro"><strong>Ergonaut One</strong></a>, a cutting-edge, open-source ergonomic wireless split mechanical keyboard that's been meticulously designed to transform the way you interact with your computer. Born from a passion for innovation and a commitment to comfort and functionality, the Ergonaut One is the latest creation from the forward-thinkers at Ergonaut Keyboards.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="the-genesis-of-ergonomics-and-aesthetics-ergonaut-one">The Genesis of Ergonomics and Aesthetics: Ergonaut One<a href="https://ergonautkb.com/ru/blog/introducing-ergonaut-one#the-genesis-of-ergonomics-and-aesthetics-ergonaut-one" class="hash-link" aria-label="Прямая ссылка на The Genesis of Ergonomics and Aesthetics: Ergonaut One" title="Прямая ссылка на The Genesis of Ergonomics and Aesthetics: Ergonaut One">​</a></h2>
<p>Our journey began with inspiration from notable projects like the <a href="https://github.com/foostan/crkbd" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>Corne by foostan</em></a> and the <a href="https://github.com/yumagulovrn/dao-choc-ble" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>Dao by yumagulovrn</em></a>. What set our hearts on fire was the idea of crafting a keyboard that didn't just look stunning but felt incredible to use. The goal was simple yet ambitious: to make an ergonomic wireless split keyboard that is affordable, visually appealing, and, above all, extremely DIY-friendly.</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="unleashing-the-features">Unleashing the Features:<a href="https://ergonautkb.com/ru/blog/introducing-ergonaut-one#unleashing-the-features" class="hash-link" aria-label="Прямая ссылка на Unleashing the Features:" title="Прямая ссылка на Unleashing the Features:">​</a></h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Low-Profile Design</strong>: Say goodbye to hand strain with our sleek low-profile Gateron switches.</li>
<li><strong>Split Personality</strong>: Customize your setup for the ultimate comfort with a split design that adapts to your workspace.</li>
<li><strong>Endurance Champion</strong>: A 250mAh battery ensures you enjoy up to a month of use between charges.</li>
<li><strong>Keycap Versatility</strong>: Express yourself with a wide range of compatible keycaps.</li>
<li><strong>Wallet-Friendly</strong>: Achieve ergonomic excellence without breaking the bank, thanks to the Seeed Studio XIAO nRF52840 MCU and a smart, one-PCB design.</li>
<li><strong>3D Printed Customizability</strong>: Apart from the PCB's, components, and hardware, personalize everything with your 3D printer.</li>
<li><strong>Beginner-Friendly</strong>: Easy-to-solder PCB and simple-to-print cases make this a perfect project for newcomers.</li>
<li><strong>Wireless Freedom</strong>: Enjoy a clutter-free desk with a design that cuts the cords.</li>
<li><strong>Open Source Spirit</strong>: Built on the CERN-OHL-P v2 license, empowering you to make it your own and even profit from your creations.</li>
</ul>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="why-gateron-low-profile">Why Gateron Low Profile?<a href="https://ergonautkb.com/ru/blog/introducing-ergonaut-one#why-gateron-low-profile" class="hash-link" aria-label="Прямая ссылка на Why Gateron Low Profile?" title="Прямая ссылка на Why Gateron Low Profile?">​</a></h2>
<p>In the year 2023, we had options, but none shone brighter than the <a href="https://ergonautkb.com/ru/docs/switches/gateron-low-profile">Gateron Low Profile</a> (GLP) switches. With the release of the improved KS33 version, the choice was clear. They offer the best tactile experience, come pre-lubed for a buttery-smooth action, and they're compatible with a plethora of MX-styled keycaps. They're a breath of fresh air compared to Cherry MX styled and Kailh Choc switches, delivering a low-profile form without sacrificing the benefits of their MX-styled counterparts.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="more-than-just-a-keyboard">More Than Just a Keyboard<a href="https://ergonautkb.com/ru/blog/introducing-ergonaut-one#more-than-just-a-keyboard" class="hash-link" aria-label="Прямая ссылка на More Than Just a Keyboard" title="Прямая ссылка на More Than Just a Keyboard">​</a></h2>
<p>The Ergonaut One is more than just a peripheral; it's a declaration that work and play can coexist on a foundation of ergonomic design and personal expression. Whether you're a programmer pounding out lines of code, a writer crafting your next novel, or a gamer on the quest for victory, the Ergonaut One is ready to be your trusty companion.</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="ready-to-join-the-revolution">Ready to Join the Revolution?<a href="https://ergonautkb.com/ru/blog/introducing-ergonaut-one#ready-to-join-the-revolution" class="hash-link" aria-label="Прямая ссылка на Ready to Join the Revolution?" title="Прямая ссылка на Ready to Join the Revolution?">​</a></h3>
<p>The Ergonaut One isn't just another keyboard — it's a community project, a hobbyist's dream, and a statement piece for your desk. It's a testament to what happens when innovation meets the open-source ethos: a product that's accessible, customizable, and, most importantly, designed with your well-being in mind.</p>
<p>Keep your eyes peeled for our launch promotions, and prepare to experience typing like never before. Embrace the comfort, style, and performance of the Ergonaut One — where your hands, your workspace, and your preferences are the priority.</p>
<p>Stay tuned, stay ergonomic, and remember: Your comfort is the key(board) to our success!</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Rekin Biznesu</name>
            <uri>https://github.com/diastremskii</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="Ergonaut One" term="Ergonaut One"/>
        <category label="announcement" term="announcement"/>
    </entry>
</feed>